toyota.ca 2019-04-12

# Privacy Policy - Toyota Canada and Toyota Credit Canada

##  Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) Privacy Policy Respecting Customer Information 

### The Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) Commitment to Your Privacy

Toyota Canada Inc. (“TCI”), which includes Toyota, Lexus and Scion brands, respects your right to privacy. This Policy outlines how TCI’s privacy principles protect your privacy as a key part of TCI’s on-going sales and services relationship with you as a valued Toyota (Lexus)(Scion) customer. The privacy principles apply to all personal information that TCI collects from customers. Personal information refers to any personally identifiable information about you. It does not include aggregate information that does not identify you specifically.

### What Personal Information Does TCI Collect?

In connection with your vehicle purchase, TCI collects the information provided by you that is necessary for your Toyota (Lexus)(Scion) dealership to complete the transaction, including your name, address, telephone number(s), email address, driver’s license and insurance information. TCI also records information respecting the vehicle purchased, the purchase price and other transaction information. TCI will also collect personal information from you through customer surveys, inquiries or requests for information and your visits to TCI web sites. You will only be asked to provide personal information in order to enable TCI to provide you with a service (such as sending you a new vehicle brochure, assisting you in contacting a dealership, or enabling you to complete online credit or job applications).

If you apply for credit with Toyota Credit Canada Inc. (“TCCI”), TCCI will obtain credit approval information from you and third parties. The full TCCI Privacy Policy, which outlines how TCCI’s privacy principles protect your privacy as a key part of its ongoing business relationship with you as a valued Toyota (Lexus)(Scion) customer, is available here: TCCI Privacy Policy.

TCI will collect information relating to your service transactions with authorized Toyota (Lexus)(Scion) dealerships. As part of TCI’s on-going efforts to better understand your automotive needs and improve the products and the quality and efficiency of TCI and TCI’s dealership’s provision of these products and services to you, TCI will, from time to time, ask you to provide information regarding your purchase preferences, demographics and lifestyle through customer surveys.

TCI will also collect any information that you provide through your customer service inquiries or when TCI responds to your requests for information.

TCI also collects information that you provide during visits to TCI web sites, including contact information, vehicle information, customer survey information, visitor’s dealership and language preferences, owner information, and contest entry information.

### How is Your Personal Information Used?

TCI may use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to complete sales and service transactions with you;
  * to respond to your requests for products, services or information;
  * to improve products and services and better understand your automotive needs, including through customer surveys;
  * to improve the operation/administration of our independently owned and operated dealer network, including quality assurance and training;
  * to administer your new vehicle warranty coverage, and/or your Extra Care Protection coverage;
  * to increase your awareness of Toyota, Lexus or Scion brand products and services; and
  * to include you in advertising or marketing campaigns to offer you TCI’s or other products and/or services where you have subscribed to such communications.

### With Whom is Your Personal Information Shared?

For the purposes outlined above TCI may share your personal information with Toyota Credit Canada Inc. and with Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) dealerships and dealer associations.

TCI will also share your information with select TCI marketing partners who may provide you with information about their products and services. You will be provided with an opportunity to opt-out of communications with TCI’s marketing partners. Your personal information may be transferred to third party service providers that TCI uses to assist in managing and processing your personal information. TCI’s third party service providers are required to use, maintain and disclose your personal information only in accordance with TCI’s instructions to them and only on TCI’s behalf.

TCI will not disclose any of your personal information to any other persons, except (i) with your prior consent; (ii) in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of one of TCI’s businesses; or (iii) as may be required or permitted by law.

### Connected Vehicle Services

If your vehicle is enabled with a factory installed telematics system also known as connected vehicle services (“CVT Services”), TCI will collect, use and share personal information and vehicle data to activate and provide the connected services, and for ancillary uses, as set out in this section of the Policy titled “Connected Vehicle Services”.

TCI may collect the following types of data and personal information in the course of providing the CVT Services: personal contact information (including name, address, phone number, email address, language preference), vehicle location; and any information you provide during a telephone call with our response centre.

We collect information about you and your vehicle several different ways: what we receive directly from you; from what you and your vehicle dealer provide to us; from your use of the CVT Services; from calls or emails between us; and from our connected vehicle service providers.

TCI collects and uses this data to deliver the following CVT Services:

  * Automatic Collision Notification
  * Emergency and Roadside Assistance
  * Stolen Vehicle Locator
  * Locating Missing Persons
  * Destination Assist
  * Other services related to or offered through the System

If you speak with the CVT Services response centre from your vehicle, you and any other person in your vehicle may be recorded for quality assurance purposes. The response centre may retain the recording for seven years or a transcript of the recording for two (2) years as required by law and to support requests from customers and law enforcement. For Automatic Collision Notification, Emergency Assistance Button, Roadside Assistance, Stolen Vehicle Locator and Destination Assist, we retain the electronic signal history from your vehicle for seven (7) years. Signal History tells us when you or your Vehicle contacted us and your Vehicle’s Location at the point of signal initiation.

You agree that, subject to applicable law, we can, use any of this information we collect to: (a) provide CVT Services to you or your vehicle (including, but not limited to, sharing that information with roadside assistance providers, emergency service providers, or others, as needed); (b) communicate with you about your account, or your vehicle; (c) check or maintain your vehicle’s factory installed telematics system; (d) analyze information about product usage, and comply with law; (e) provide information about you to your dealer in connection with your Vehicle; (f) provide information about you to our business partners to fulfill any request you may make and improve our service to you; (h) evaluate and improve our Service; (i) enforce the related CVT Services Terms and Conditions; (j) prevent fraud or misuse of Services; (k) comply with law, legal process or litigation; (l) protect the rights, property, or safety of you or others; (m) offer you new or additional products or services; (n) perform market research; or (o) respond to requests from TCCI about the location of your vehicle as otherwise provided in this Agreement.

TCI engages third-party service providers to assist in delivering the CVT Services. As such, we may share personal information with our service providers who will only use the personal information for the purpose of providing the CVT Services.

### Does TCI Transfer Information Outside of Canada?

The personal information that you provide to TCI may be transferred outside of Canada for processing. TCI may store personal information on servers located in other jurisdictions, including the United States. Please note that the privacy laws in such jurisdictions differ from Canadian privacy laws and that in some jurisdictions your personal information may be accessed by law enforcement authorities or the courts.

If you would like to obtain more information about TCI’s policies and practices with respect to the transfer and processing of personal information outside of Canada, please contact TCI in any of the ways described below at “How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information”.

### Your Consent

Your consent may be given expressly or implied, depending on the circumstances.

In connection with your vehicle purchase or certain service requests you will be asked to consent expressly to TCI’s collection of personal information for the purposes identified herein.

When you visit TCI’s web sites (www.toyota.ca, www.lexus.ca, www.scion.ca, www.clubtoyota.ca, and www.clublexus.ca) you consent to TCI’s collection, use and disclosure of your personal information that you provide on the web site. In some cases the web site may prompt you to provide your consent to the collection of certain personally identifiable information. By clicking “I have read and I agree” you are giving TCI permission, as applicable, to collect, use and disclose your personal information as described above under the headings “What Personal Information Does TCI Collect”, “How is Your Personal Information Used” “With Whom is Your Personal Information Shared?”.

In other cases, your consent is understood, such as when you respond to a customer satisfaction survey, request a product information brochure from the web site, register for updates on the web site or complete an online job application.

By providing any personal information in any email request or any interactive activities on TCI’s web site you consent to TCI’s collection of that information.

You may at any time withdraw or change your consent to TCI’s use or disclosure of your personal information, or request TCI to delete it from TCI’s files, subject to legal and contractual restrictions. However, if you do not provide personal information required to supply a product or service, TCI may not be able to provide that product or service.

Unless you request TCI not to do so, you agree that TCI may use and disclose to TCCI , to Toyota (Lexus)(Scion) dealerships and to dealer associations your personal information for the purposes of selectively including you in advertising and marketing campaigns designed to increase the awareness of Toyota, Lexus or Scion brand products and services and the goodwill associated with TCI’s businesses. Some of TCI’s advertising and marketing campaigns include sending out Toyota, Lexus or Scion newsletters, service reminders and promotional offers. If you would prefer that TCI not use your personally identifiable information for such advertising or marketing campaigns, please contact TCI in any of the ways described below under the heading “How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information”. You may notify TCI that you do not wish us to use your personal information for any purposes that are not required to supply you with a product or service at any time by contacting us in any of the ways described below under the heading “How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information”. TCI will seek your further consent to any additional uses of personal information for which TCI has not obtained your consent previously.

### Your Consent and Electronic Messages

TCI will only send email, text or other electronic messages to you if you have existing vehicle warranty and/or Extra Care Protection coverage or some other form of business relationship with TCI, or have asked for or otherwise agreed to receive emails, texts or other electronic messages from TCI. Any electronic message that you receive from TCI will identify TCI as the sender, enable you to contact TCI directly and provide for a means of unsubscribing from further electronic messages. TCI may also from time to time request your consent on behalf of any of or all of TCCI, Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) dealerships and dealer associations, and Toyota marketing partners. Electronic messages that you receive from any of these entities will identify the sender, enable you to contact the sender directly and provide for a means of unsubscribing from further electronic messages from the sender, and in the case of Toyota marketing partners, unsubscribe from all Toyota marketing partner electronic messages.

### TCI’s Web Sites

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information.** When you visit TCI’s web sites, unless you tell TCI who you are or reveal any other personal information, TCI does not collect or store any information about you. The only information TCI collects and stores is non-personally identifiable information such as the name of your Internet service provider, the type of the Internet browser you used, and referring web site and the pages you request. TCI uses this non-personally identifiable information to generate aggregate statistics regarding TCI’s web site activity.

**Cookies.** Cookies are files that your web browser places on your computer's hard drive that permit TCI to tell whether, and if so, how many times, you have accessed TCI’s web sites previously, your language of choice, your dealer of choice, the province in which your internet provider resides, internet user behavioral analysis, and your computer system’s flash preference. You may choose to decline to accept cookies if your browser permits but doing so may affect your use of TCI’s web sites and your ability to access certain features of the web sites.

**Pixel tags.** A pixel tag is a transparent graphic image, sometimes called a web beacon, clear GIFs or tracking beacon, placed on a web site or in an e-mail, which indicates to us that a page or e-mail has been viewed. In addition, a pixel tag may tell your browser to get content from another server.

**Third-Party Links.** TCI’s web sites contain links to other sites. When you click on links that take you to third party web sites, you will be subject to the third parties' privacy policies. While TCI supports the protection of privacy on the Internet, TCI is not responsible for the actions of third parties or for their privacy practices. TCI encourages the users of its web sites to be aware when they leave the web sites and to read the privacy policies of each and every web site with which they interact.

**Children.** TCI does not use its web sites to knowingly solicit personal information from or to market to persons under the age of majority.

### Advertising/Behavioral Targeting; How To Opt-Out

TCI licenses technology to serve advertisements on its own web sites and within its content as that content is served across the Internet.

Ad network providers, data providers, publishers and other media-related companies, and/or analytics service providers may set and access their own cookies, pixel tags and similar technologies on your device’s web browser and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you. We and they may use information about your browsing behavior on one or multiple devices to establish an online profile and to target advertisements for products and services in which you might be interested based on your visits to both the TCI web sites and other web sites. We and they may use a variety of companies to serve advertisements.

If you prefer not to allow TCI to use these technologies to collect or use your personal information for the purposes of targeted advertising on TCI’s web sites, you may opt-out by clicking here. If you prefer not to allow TCI, or third parties acting on TCI’s behalf, to use these technologies to collect or use your personal information for purposes of targeted advertising on third-party websites, you may opt-out by following the procedure on the NAI Opt-Out Page.

These opt-outs will not be effective if your browser is configured to reject cookies, or if you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different computer or change browsers. 

In addition, TCI may use third-party ad networks, publishers and other entities to serve advertisements and third party analytics vendors to evaluate and provide us with information about the use of the TCI web sites and viewing of our content. For example, we may share personal information with third parties (e.g., social media sites, other advertisers, advertising agencies, advertising networks, data exchanges, etc.) in order to deliver to you content on our website or third party sites. For information about your ability to opt-out of this, please contact us at [socialmedia@toyota.ca](mailto:socialmedia@toyota.ca)

Please note that even if you opt-out, you will still see advertisements while you're browsing online. However the advertisements you see may be less relevant to you and your interests. Additionally, many network advertising programs allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. The NAI Opt-Out Page provides a tool that identifies its member companies that have cookies on your browser and provides links to those companies. 

Moreover, if you would like to access and/or delete any personal information that Google (one of our analytics and ad service partners) holds about you, then you may do so via [“My Activity”](https://myactivity.google.com/myactivity). 

### How Long Does TCI Retain Your Personal information?

TCI retains your personal information as long as is required for the purposes identified when you provided the personal information and for any new purposes identified and consented to by you, and for an appropriate time thereafter.

Your personal information will be kept in files stored on TCI’s databases located at TCI’s head office located in Toronto, Ontario.

### How Does TCI Protect Your Personal Information?

TCI protects your personal information using security systems appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. TCI’s web sites are members of the Entrust Digital Certificate Program which involves applying security sockets layer software encryption technology to all information that you submit through the web sites. TCI applies security safeguards required for compliance with the Entrust Digital Certificate Program. Please note: You are solely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password(s).

### How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information

You may review, update or correct any of your personal information held in TCI’s files and your consents regarding its use and disclosure at any time by contacting TCI’s Privacy Officer in any of the ways indicated below.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding TCI’s policy and procedures, if you wish to change your consent to TCI’s use and disclosure of your information, or if you wish to review, update, correct or have TCI delete your information from files, please contact:

Privacy Officer   
Toyota Canada Inc.  
One Toyota Place  
Toronto, Ontario  
M1H 1H9  

by telephone: [Dial and Call 1-888-TOYOTA-8](tel:18888696828) or [Dial and Call 1-800-26-LEXUS](tel:18002653987) or [Dial and Call 1-866-9-SCION-1](tel:18669724661)  
or by visiting us at toyota.ca or lexus.ca or scion.ca

### Will TCI’s Privacy Policy Change?

TCI reserves the right, at any time, to modify this Policy at TCI’s sole discretion, and you agree to be bound by any such modifications, which shall be effective immediately upon TCI posting the revised Policy on TCI’s web sites.

**POSTED: April 2017**

##  TCCI Privacy Policy  
Privacy Policy Statement 

#### Toyota Credit Canada Inc.

Toyota Credit Canada Inc. ("TCCI") operates throughout Canada under the business name of "Toyota Financial Services" and "Lexus Financial Services." TCCI is the financial services provider of Toyota Canada Inc.

### This Statement

As a provider of financial services, the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information is very important to our day-to-day business operations. The purpose of this Privacy Policy Statement ("Statement") is to inform you of the specific types of personal information we collect, why we collect it, how it is used, how it is disclosed and how you may correct errors in your personal information collected by us.

The full Toyota Canada Inc. Privacy Policy, which outlines how Toyota Canada Inc.’s privacy principles protect your privacy as a key part of the Toyota Canada Inc. on-going sales and service relationship with you as a valued Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) customer, is available here at: www.toyota.ca.

We understand the importance of your personal information and take pride in our commitment to maintaining its confidentiality. We ensure that your personal information is collected, used and disclosed only in the manner in which you have consented. Our organization ensures that we meet or exceed the requirements of all laws and regulations applicable in Canada. 

### What is "Personal Information"?

"Personal information" is any personally identifiable information about you, which may include, but is not limited to, your name, mailing address, credit history, credit card number, banking information and voice recordings as well as the terms of your financing and lease agreements (as applicable). It does not include aggregated information that does not identify you specifically.

### How Do We Collect Personal Information?

When you finance or lease a vehicle through us, we will collect the personal information you provide to us in your credit application. Your personal information is also collected when you enter into a finance or lease agreement with us.

We may also collect information during our interactions with you for our mutual protection including, monitoring or recording your telephone discussions with our representatives for servicing accuracy, quality assurance and/or for training purposes.

We may also collect your personal information from third parties including, but not limited to, third parties referenced on your credit application and other credit providers or credit bureaus, however, your consent will have always been obtained prior to any third parties being approached. For example, when you have given us your consent to contact your references or your employer by providing us with their contact information on your credit application. 

### How is Your Personal Information Used and Disclosed?

We may use and share your personal information with Toyota Canada Inc. and with your Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) dealer and the third parties described below, for the following purposes:

  1. to help us evaluate your credit application to finance or lease a vehicle through us.
  2. to credit bureaus, consumer reporting agencies and other credit providers for the purpose of evaluating your credit application and confirming, verifying and updating any information (including but not limited to, your account balance and payment record) provided to us regarding your credit application or your finance or lease agreement.
  3. to the dealer for the purpose of assessing your credit application and/or informing them of our decision on your credit application.
  4. account administration, including collection of overdue accounts, audit and archival purposes.
  5. to third party service providers for the purpose of collecting on an overdue account, for registering our security interest on your vehicle and to confirm that valid insurance has been purchased for your vehicle.
  6. third party service providers for the administration of optional products and services that you have purchased.
  7. to a third party in connection with a transfer or assignment by us of our interest in your lease or finance agreement, including securitization transactions.
  8. to administer your new vehicle warranty coverage, and/or your Extra Care Protection coverage, as applicable, and as required by law. 
  9. to include you in any advertising or marketing campaigns in which we alone or, together with Toyota Canada Inc. and its dealers, offer you our or their products and/or services.
  10. to respond to your requests for products, services or information, and improve our services, information and products, including asking you to reply to customer surveys.
  11. to better understand your automotive needs and to increase your awareness of Toyota, Lexus or Scion brand products and services and the goodwill associated with our businesses.

### Your Consent

We will only collect, use and disclose your personal information with your consent.

Your consent may be given expressly or implied, depending on the circumstances. In connection with your credit application and financing or lease agreements you will be asked to consent expressly to our collection of personal information for the purposes identified herein. In other cases, your consent is understood, such as when you respond to a customer satisfaction survey, request a product information brochure from our web site, register for updates on the web site or speak with our representatives after having being notified that the call may be recorded.

Customers who prefer not to have their calls recorded can conduct their business with us in writing or you can immediately advise the Customer Service representative that you do not wish to be recorded and we will ensure that procedures are activated to comply with your request.

You may notify us that you do not wish us to use your personal information for any purposes that are not required to supply you with a product or service at any time by contacting us in any of the ways described below under the heading "How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information". We will seek your further consent to any additional uses of personal information for which we have not obtained your consent previously.

Subject to legal and contractual restrictions, you may at any time withdraw or change your consent to our use or disclosure of your personal information, or request us to delete it from our files. However, if you do not provide personal information required to supply a product or service or withdraw or change your consent, we may not be able to provide that product or service. Notwithstanding any withdrawal of consent, we may retain and use your information for account administration purposes, including collection of any amounts you owe us.

### With Whom is Your Personal Information Shared?

For the purposes outlined above we may share your personal information with Toyota Canada Inc., with the Toyota (Lexus) (Scion) dealer and with third parties. We will not disclose any of your personal information to any other persons except with your prior express consent, or in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of one of our businesses, or as may be required or permitted by law. 

Your personal information may be transferred to third party service providers that we use to assist in managing and processing your personal information. Our third party service providers are required to use, maintain and disclose your personal information only in accordance with our instructions to them and only on our behalf.

We will also share your information with our joint-marketing partners who may provide you with information about their products and services. You will be provided with an opportunity to opt-out of communications with our joint-marketing partners.

### Does TCCI Transfer Information Outside of Canada?

The personal information that you provide to TCCI may be transferred outside of Canada for storage and processing. TCCI uses service providers that store and process your personal information on servers located in the United States. When TCCI uses service providers to store and process your personal information, TCCI's policy is to have appropriate contractual provisions in place with those service providers limiting the purposes for which your personal information is being transferred to them and stipulating security requirements for that information. Please note that the privacy laws in other jurisdictions may differ from Canadian privacy laws and in some jurisdictions your personal information may be accessed by law enforcement authorities or the courts. If you have any questions regarding our policies and practices relating to storage and processing of personal information outside of Canada, please contact us in any of the ways described below under "How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information".

### How Long Do We Retain Your Personal information?

We retain your personal information as long as is required for the purposes identified when you provided the personal information and for any new purposes identified by us and consented to by you, and for an appropriate time thereafter.

Your personal information will be kept in files stored on our databases located at our Toyota Canada Inc. and TCCI head office in Toronto and Markham, Ontario.

### How Do We Protect Your Personal Information?

We protect your personal information using security systems appropriate to the sensitivity of the information. In our ongoing effort to safeguard your personal information from unauthorized collection, use or disclosure, we have put in a number of safeguards including; contractual, organizational, structural and technological security standards.

### How You Can Review and Update Your Personal Information

You may review, update or correct any of your personal information held in our files and your consent regarding its use and disclosure at any time by contacting us in any of the ways indicated below. Please note, we rely primarily on you to provide us with your most complete, accurate and up-to-date personal information and to inform us of any changes to your personal information.

If you wish to change your consent to our use and disclosure of your information, or if you wish to review, update, correct or have us delete your information from our files, please contact us as follows:

Customer Service Manager  
Toyota Credit Canada Inc.  
80 Micro Court, Suite 200  
Markham, Ontario  
L3R 9Z5 

or by telephone: [Dial and Call 1-888-TOYOTA-8](tel:18888696828) or [Dial and Call 1-800-26-LEXUS](tel:18002653987) or [Dial and Call 1-866-9-SCION-1](tel:18669724661) or by visiting us at www.privacy.toyotafinancialservices.ca, www.privacy.lexusfinancialservices.ca or www.scion.ca/privacy_tcci

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Statement and procedures, please contact:

Privacy Officer  
Toyota Credit Canada Inc.  
80 Micro Court, Suite 200  
Markham, Ontario  
L3R 9Z5 

### Will this Statement Change?

We reserve the right, at any time, to modify this Statement at our sole discretion, and you agree to be bound by any such modifications, which shall be effective immediately upon our posting the revised Statement on our web site.

POSTED: December 1, 2014

## Entune Privacy Policy

### This Privacy Notice Applies To Vehicles Equipped With Connected Vehicle Services

When you purchased or leased your vehicle, you had the opportunity to subscribe for Connected Vehicle Services that offer peace of mind, convenience and infotainment in one comprehensive package. Examples of the Services include live, 24-hour navigation assistance, integration of popular mobile apps and emergency services at the press of a button.

We provide you with these Services by using and managing your Personal Information and Vehicle Data.

### Personal Information

_This Notice DOES NOT apply to data collection unrelated to Connected Vehicle Services on Toyota or Lexus websites, or on sites that we do not own, operate or control._  

Data that identifies you as an individual is considered to be Personal Information. Examples are name, address, phone number, email address.

### Vehicle Data

_This Notice DOES NOT apply to data collection unrelated to Connected Vehicle Services on Toyota or Lexus websites, or on sites that we do not own, operate or control._  

Data generated by the computers in your Vehicle is considered to be Vehicle Data such as Location Data.

### What Are Connected Vehicle Services?

Toyota and Lexus vehicles are equipped with technology that electronically transmits information about your Vehicle to us such that we can provide you with benefits.

To learn whether your Vehicle is equipped with Connected Services, and whether it is active or inactive, contact your Dealer or our Customer Service Team.

### Vehicle Data = Benefits for You

  * Respond to Vehicle Emergencies
  * Finds Destinations Your Request
  * Provide Vehicle Finder Applications
  * Improve Safety
  * Develop New Vehicles and Features
  * Confirm vehicle quality
  * Analyze Vehicle Trends

### We Protect Your Vehicle Data

We continuously strive to protect your Vehicle Data. We use a dedicated private and secure wireless network. Your Vehicle is designed only to respond to commands from us and only for those features we provide, such as vehicle location.

### We Protect Your Personal Information

Your contact information (name, address, phone number, email), provided when you subscribe for Connected Vehicle Services, is retained in secure servers.

### We Collect and Use

  * Personal Information 
    * When you subscribe, we collect your name, address, phone number, email address, language preference and other personal information you may choose to share with us to provide Connected Vehicle Services and communicate with you. 
  * Location Data 
    * Your Vehicle may send an electronic signal with your latitude and longitude at a particular point in time (“Location Data”) to our Response Center under certain specific circumstances. We record and transmit your Location Data when you contact us for emergencies, roadside assistance, stolen or missing vehicle and destination services. 
    * Your GPS Navigation is equipped with a traffic feature that automatically collects and transmits, through GPS technology, your Location Data, travel direction and speed to support HD traffic and weather information available in your Vehicle. It is not tied to your VIN or personal information. 

### We Also Use Your Vehicle Data To:

  * Improve Safety
  * Develop New Vehicles and Features
  * Prevent Fraud or Misuse
  * Support Laws and Legal Process

### Storing of Personal Information

We store your Personal Information for 7 years after expiration of your subscription.

### Vehicle Data

  * Location Data 
    * We store your Location Data from the time you contact us until 7 years after expiration of your subscription for emergency, roadside assistance, stolen or missing vehicle and destination services. 
  * Voice Recordings 
    * If you speak with the Response Center from your Vehicle, your conversation may be recorded and stored for 2 years 
  * Exception 

There’s an exception to these rules.

    * Sometimes we are required to keep your Personal Information or Vehicle Data for much longer periods of time. This only occurs if mandated by law or legal process or in the event of litigation 

### Sharing of Personal Information

We share your Personal Information with:

  * Emergency Responders 
    * To provide emergency assistance to you. This includes Roadside Assistance Providers. 
  * Our Affiliates 
    * To verify fraud or repossess in the event of a breach of your lease or finance contract and to support vehicle improvement. 
  * Toyota Motor Corporation 
    * To support safety, research, analysis and product development efforts made by our parent company. 
  * Third Party Service Providers 
    * We contractually bind third parties to handle your data in accordance with Toyota standards described in this Notice. For example, Sirius XM Connected Vehicle Services Inc. provides customer support and the other services that are a part of your Connected Vehicle Services. 
  * Law Enforcement 
    * We DON’T share with law enforcement unless we are required to do so by law or legal process, in response to government investigations, as may be required for national security, or where we believe necessary to prevent harm, injury or loss. 

We DON'T share your Personal Information with:

  * Data Resellers
  * Social Networks
  * Ad Networks

We share with you and various third parties:

  * Location Data 

We share your Location Data with:

    * Emergency responders
    * Roadside assistance providers
    * Law enforcement
    * Our affiliate, Toyota Credit Canada Inc.
    * Our third party service providers acting on our behalf
  * Voice Recordings 
    * We share Voice Recordings with you and law enforcement to support requests related to litigation and investigations. We may also share them with our third party service providers, acting on our behalf. 

### Security

We take information security seriously.

We continuously strive to protect your Personal Information and Vehicle Data by employing our industry’s best practices through our formal security program.

Our formal security program includes

  * System Defenses - We designed the Connected Vehicle Services technology in your Vehicle to resist security vulnerabilities. We employ layers of defense to drive strong safeguarding practices including code and design reviews, regularly scheduled security testing, firewalls, intrusion detection systems and encryption. 
  * Private Network – “When your Vehicle Data is transmitted from your Vehicle to us, we use a dedicated private wireless network. In addition, your Vehicle is designed only to respond to commands from us and only for those available features we provide including vehicle location.” 
  * No Warranties – Please note, however, we cannot completely ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us by you or your Vehicle. Your use of your Vehicle’s Connected Vehicle Services is at your own risk. You have the option to deactivate your Connected Vehicle Services by contacting us and requesting deactivation. If you choose to deactivate your system, you may lose features such as Safety Connect including ACN 

### Choices

  * Opt In/Opt Out - If you choose to deactivate your system, you may lose features such as Safety Connect including ACN
  * Review and Update - You may also review and update your Personal Information at any time by contacting us.
  * Deactivation – When you buy a vehicle equipped with Connected Vehicle Services, data collection is active. You may deactivate Connected Vehicle Services at any time by contacting us and we will no longer collect your Personal Information and Vehicle Data. 

### Consent:

When you purchased or leased a vehicle equipped with Connected Vehicle Services, you were asked by your Dealer to sign a Connected Vehicle Services Agreement. Our Privacy Policy is part of that Agreement.

Click here to see our Privacy Policy.

NOTE: If you did not accept the Agreement, please notify us within 15 days of taking delivery of the vehicle and we will cancel your Services. Failure to cancel your Services within 15 days of receipt of the Agreement will be deemed acceptance of the Agreement.
